I had the craziest dream last night.
昨晚我做了一個瘋狂至極的夢
I was dancing the White Swan.
我扮演著「白天鵝」
It was different choreography, though. It was more like the Bolshoi's.
編舞不太一樣，有點像莫斯科大劇院的版本
It was the prologue,
那是序幕中的一場戲
when Rothbart casts his spell.
魔法師羅斯巴種下了詛咒
Look how pink. So pretty...
粉粉的，好漂亮…
Pretty!
真漂亮！
- You're in a good mood. - He promised to feature me more this season.
- 你今天心情不錯 - 他答應我，這一季讓我演大角色
Well, he certainly should.
早該如此
You've been there long enough,
你在團裡熬了那麼久
and you're the most dedicated dancer in the company.
你是最努力的舞蹈演員
Up.
起來
- What's that? - What?
- 那是什麼？ - 怎麼啦？
There.
背後
Nothing.
沒關係
You're sure you don't want me to come with you?
你真不要我陪你去？
You're a sweet girl.
乖女兒
Did you see Beth today?
你今天看見貝絲了嗎？
I can't believe she's back.
她居然還有臉回來
- Of course she's back. - What, she can't take a hint?
- 回來很正常啊 - 不會吧，她還沒看出來？
The company is broke. No one comes to see her anymore.
咱們團要破產了，她過氣了
Oh, nobody actually comes to see ballet full stop.
如今，能堅持看完整場芭蕾的人沒有嘍
That's not true. I heard The Royal had one of their best seasons yet.
才不是呢 皇家芭蕾舞團上一季不知道有多火爆！
He just needs to try something new. That's all.
他得換點新花樣，沒別的
No, someone new.
不是換新花樣，得換新人
- Like who? - Like someone who's not approaching menopause.
- 換成誰？ - 老女人肯定不行
It's sad.
真讓人難過
What's sad?
難過什麼？
Beth's such a beautiful dancer.
貝絲多美啊！
Yeah, so is my grandmother.
是啊，我奶奶也不醜
- Well Fonteyn danced into her fifties. - Yeah, we know.
- 瑪格·芳廷一直跳到了50歲 - 是，我們知道 （瑪格·芳廷，英國人，20世紀最優秀的芭蕾舞演員之一）
Great.
太好了
Thought I'd fucking missed my stop.
我他媽坐過了站
It's a hell-fit all the way from 79th.
從79街一路狂奔過來
Beautiful as always, Nina.
跳得很好，尼娜
Relax.
放鬆
And one, and two, and three, and four.
一、二、三、四
Stop, John. One second.
約翰，停一下
Okay, take position.
準備，各就各位
And one, and two, and three, and up.
一、二、三、起
And one, and two, and three, and four.
一、二、三、四
Hello, dear.
你好，親愛的
We all know the story.
故事情節耳熟能詳
Virginal girl, pure and sweet,
純美無暇的纖纖處子
trapped in the body of a swan.
被壞人變成了一隻天鵝
She desires freedom
她渴望自由
that only true love can break the spell.
但只有真愛才能解除魔咒
Her wish is nearly granted in the form of a Prince.
王子的到來，使她的願望幾乎成真
But before he can declare his love,
可就在，他要表白真愛之際
The lustful twin, the Black Swan, tricks and seduces him.
淫邪的黑天鵝，施展手段迷惑了他
Devastated, the White Swan leaps off a cliff,
白天鵝悲痛欲絕，跳崖自盡
killing herself. And in death...
在死亡裡…
finds freedom.
她得到了解脫
- Good morning, company. - Good morning.
- 早上好，團員們 - 早上好
We will open our season with Swan Lake.
這一季的開幕戲是「天鵝湖」
Done to death, I know.
我知道，「天鵝湖」是部老戲
But not like this.
但這部不同
We strip it down, make it visceral and real.
我們重新改編，使愛更真，情更切
A new production needs a new Swan Queen.
這部新作品需要一個新的天鵝女王
A fresh face to present to the world.
我要向世界展示一張全新的面孔
But... Which of you can embody both Swans?
不過…你們有誰可以同時演繹兩個角色？
The White, and the Black.
白天鵝，和黑天鵝
All the soloists I tapped:
我剛才用手拍過的演員：
Go to your scheduled rehearsals this afternoon.
下午照常綵排
And the girls I didn't tap:
而我沒拍過的女演員：
Meet me in the principals' studio at 5:00.
下午5點到主角排練室見我
Thank you.
謝謝各位
All right.
好了
- Let's go. Did we do left side? - Yes, mistress.
- 繼續，剛才是左側練習嗎？ - 是的，老師
Fuck! Fuck!
該死！該死！
What?
看什麼？
If I was only casting the White Swan, she'd be yours.
如果只是選白天鵝，你是不二人選
But I'm not.
可現在不是
Maestro, Odile's coda, please.
音樂老師，奧黛兒之終篇，謝謝
Now show me your Black Swan, Nina.
讓我看看你的黑天鵝，尼娜
Not so controlled. Seduce us.
放開，誘惑我們
Not just the Prince, but the court, the audience, the entire world.
不僅要誘惑王子 還有在場的人，觀眾，整個世界
Come on, like a spider spinning a web.
加油，要像一隻結網的蜘蛛
Attack it, attack it! Come on!
強一點！強一點！加油！
Well...
好的...
- Good of you to join us. - Sorry...
- 大駕光臨 - 對不起…
Girls, this is Lily.
姑娘們，這位是莉莉
Straight off the plane from San Francisco. She's filling Rebecca's old spot.
她從舊金山來，填補麗貝卡的位子
- Hey. - Get warmed up.
去熱熱身
No, it's okay.
不用，沒關係
I'm good.
不用熱身
Should I go again?
需要我再來一次嗎？
No, thanks, Nina. I've seen enough.
不用，謝謝你，尼娜，夠了
Veronica, the White Swan variation.
維羅妮卡，白天鵝變奏曲
Come on, come on, come on, please.
快點，快點，快點
All right, Maestro.
好了，音樂老師
Two, three...
二、三…
So how'd it go?
面試怎麼樣？
You were late, so I called Susie in the office.
你回來晚了，我給辦公室的蘇茜打了電話
An audition! I can't believe he just sprang that on you.
面試！真不敢相信，他讓你面試主角
So?
怎麼樣？
It was fine.
還好
Just fine?
還好？
Oh, sweetheart...
小寶貝…
You tell me about it.
別急，慢慢說
Nina, everything all right?
尼娜，沒事吧？
I'm fine.
我沒事
Almost done.
快好了
You're working yourself too hard.
你練得太猛了
- We all have off days. - That girl, um, barged in.
- 我們都有不在狀態的時候 - 那個女孩，突然闖了進來
I'm sure she didn't mean to.
我相信她不是有意的
For a starter, if I hadn't taken you to each of your classes, you'd have been completely lost.
你剛跳舞那會 如果我不領著你去教室，你一定迷路
I'm going to talk to him tomorrow. I'm going to tell him I finished it.
明天我去找他，我要告訴他，我做到了
You don't need to lie.
沒必要撒謊
You won't convince him one way or the other.
他不會相信的
Oh, sweetheart.
寶貝
I know it's disappointing.
我知道這讓你很沮喪
When you start getting older, there's all this
年紀一大，種種壓力…
ridiculous pressure. God knows I understand.
如影隨形，我太瞭解啦
But it's all right.
不過，沒關係
No matter what.
不管怎樣
You'll probably get to dance the part of the cat again.
你也許會再演貓那個角色
That's such a wonderful part.
那個角色真不錯
Or maybe he'll make you a big swan.
或者，他會讓你演大天鵝
Either way, you'll shine.
不管怎樣，你都會光彩照人
You know...
我知道
Everything will be better in the morning.
一覺醒來，一切會變得更美好
It always is.
一定會的
Sweet girl.
乖女兒
Yes, Nina?
有事嗎？尼娜
Do you have a minute?
你現在有空嗎？
- Now's not a good time. I get it. - Now is perfect.
- 我知道你很忙 - 不，時間正合適
So...
那...
I just wanted to tell you that
我想告訴你
I practiced the coda last night and
昨晚，我又練了一次終篇
I finished.
我完成了
I thought you should know.
我想讓你知道
Okay, Nina, listen. Honestly, I don't care about your technique.
尼娜，聽著，老實說 我關心的不是你的技巧
- You should know that by now. - Yeah, but yesterday...
- 這一點你要明白 - 可昨天…
No. Anyway...
別說了，還有…
I've already chosen Veronica. Sorry.
我已經選了維羅妮卡，抱歉
Sorry.
抱歉
Okay, thank you.
明白了，謝謝你
That's it?
放棄了？
You're not going to try and change my mind?
不試一試說服我，讓我改變心意嗎？
You must have thought it was possible.
我也許真得會改變心意
Otherwise, what are you doing here all dolled up?
不然，幹嘛打扮的這麼漂亮到這來？
I came to ask for the part.
我想要這個角色
Well...
好吧...
The truth is...
老實說…
When I look at you, all I see is the White Swan.
我一直認為，你很適合白天鵝
Yes, you're beautiful, fearful, fragile.
你美麗，怯懦，嬌柔
Ideal casting.
演白天鵝最合適
But the Black Swan? It's a hard fucking job to dance both.
可黑天鵝怎麼辦？一人飾兩角，很難的
I can dance the Black Swan, too.
黑天鵝我也能跳
Really?
真的嗎？
In four years, every time you dance,
這四年來，你每一次跳黑天鵝…
I see obsess getting each and every move perfectly right, but I never see you lose yourself.
關心地總是每個動作的完美 但我卻從沒看見過你的激情
Ever. All that discipline for what?
從沒見過，為什麼會這樣？
- I just want to be perfect. - You what?
- 我想要完美 - 什麼？
I want to be perfect.
我想要完美
Perfection is not just about control.
完美不是控制出來
It's also about letting go.
是爆發出來的
Surprise yourself so you can surprise the audience. Transcendence.
超越自我，征服自己，征服觀眾
And very few have it in them.
能做到的人不多
I think I do have it in me.
我認為我能做到
You bit me?
你咬我？
I can't believe you bit me!
你居然咬我！
I'm sorry.
對不起
Man, that fucking hurt!
老天，真他媽疼！
What?
看什麼？
Why's she always staring at me?
她為什麼總盯著我？
Hey, it's been posted.
結果出來了
Veronica.
維羅妮卡
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Hey!
嘿!
Why would you say that?
為什麼胡說八道？
Your idea of some sick joke?
耍我嗎？
What?
你說什麼？
Fuck you.
去死吧
Hey, Nina!
尼娜！
Congratulations!
恭喜！
You're so beautiful.
你好漂亮
- Hello? - Hi.
喂？
What is it? What's wrong?
怎麼了，有麻煩？
I'm fine.
我很好
He picked me, Mom.
他選了我，媽媽
Do you hear me?
你能聽見嗎？
- For Swan Lake? - I'm going to be Swan Queen!
- 跳天鵝湖？ - 我要跳天鵝女王啦！
Mom!
媽媽！
I'll be home soon. I just wanted to let you know.
我一會就回來，想提前讓你知道
- I love you. - I love you, too.
- 我愛你 - 我也愛你
Mom?
媽媽？
Mom, are you in your room?
媽媽，你在你房間嗎？
Nina?
尼娜？
Are you home?
你在家嗎？
Nina, when you get out I'm in the kitchen.
尼娜，我在廚房等你
Come on, sweetie.
快來，寶貝
My daughter, the Swan Queen.
我的女兒，天鵝女王
It's our favorite. Vanilla with strawberry filling.
我們的最愛，香草藍莓餡蛋糕
Oh, Mom, not too big.
媽媽，別切太大
Oh, that's way, way too much.
太多了…
- It's a celebration. It's just this once. - Mom...
- 我們在慶祝，就吃這一次 - 媽媽…
My stomach's still in knots.
我的胃不舒服
Fine.
好
Then it's garbage!
倒了！
No, Mom, don't. I'm sorry.
不要，媽媽，不要，對不起
I'm just... I'm just so proud of you.
我太為你驕傲了
It looks so yummy.
看起來真好吃
Okay, okay.
好，好
Thank you. Thank you.
謝謝，謝謝
Thank you, Nina.
謝謝你，尼娜
That's very nice.
非常好
But I knew the White Swan wouldn't be a problem.
我知道白天鵝不成問題
The real work will your metamorphosis into her evil twin.
你的任務是如何蛻變成邪惡的黑天鵝
And I know I saw a flash of her yesterday.
昨天我看見了她的影子
So get ready to give me more of that bite.
再加一把勁
Excellent.
非常好
That evil force is pulling you that you can't escape. That's just out of your control.
邪惡力量牽扯你，無法逃離，難以抵制
So you sense it, you get aware of it more: "It's taking me, it's taking me."
你的感覺越來越清晰 「它在佔有我，佔有我」
A little bit more desperate.
多一絲絕望
Right, and you can maybe go up a little bit and then come down, and then...
對，你可以揮高一些，然後放下…
That's it.
就是這樣
Watch the way she moves.
瞧她的動作
Imprecise, but effortless.
不精準，卻很輕盈
She's not faking it.
真實無虛
Gorgeous! Okay, that's beautiful.
非常漂亮！好，漂亮
Let's start again from the beginning.
從頭再來一遍
You'll room with Beth from now on, so be considerate.
從現在起，你和貝絲一個化妝間，小心點
Thanks, Susie.
謝謝，蘇茜
Those are for you, from Mr. Leroy.
這是盧萊先生送給你的
They're beautiful.
真漂亮
I'll be back in a second.
我一會就來
Let me come back to you, please.
失陪一會
Let's go.
我們走
Ready to be thrown to the wolves?
準備好讓這群狼品頭論足了嗎？
We need our cash, so please don't forget to smile.
我們需要錢，保持微笑
Ladies and gentlemen, please, may I have your attention?
女士們先生們，請靜一靜，好嗎？
Good evening.
晚上好
Let me make this very important announcement.
我想宣佈一件非常重要的事
You all had had the chance and the privilege to be enchanted, transported,
有一個人的表演曾讓各位目眩神迷 情難自禁
and even sometimes devastated, by the performances
有時甚至是悲痛欲絕
of this true artist of our company.
她是真正的藝術家
She's been a crucial inspiration to my work.
也是我作品靈感的源泉
A role model to all dancers, and even more than that,
她是眾舞者的榜樣，更是…
a deeply appreciated presence on our stage.
舞台上最值得欣賞的一抹芳姿
You all know who I am talking about.
你們都知道我說得是誰
Ladies and gentlemen, Beth Macintyre.
女士們先生們，貝絲·麥金泰爾
But as we all know,
不過，我們知道
every great career has to come to an end.
每個偉大的事業都有結束的一天
Beth is retiring at the end of season.
貝絲將於本季末退出舞台
She will be giving her farewell performance as Melpomene,
並在「悲劇女神」中作告別演出
the role she originated in my first ballet.
這也是我的第一支芭蕾舞劇
My little princess,
我的小公主
we honor you. You will be greatly missed,
我們向你致敬，將你深深懷念
and never forgotten.
永記心間
But as we bid adieu to one star, we welcome another.
不過，江山代有才人出
We're opening our season with my new version of Swan Lake.
這一季我們將推出新版「天鵝湖」
Taking the role of our new Swan Queen, the exquisite Nina Sayers.
領銜主演「天鵝女王」的 是這位楚楚動人的尼娜·塞耶斯
You'll soon have the pleasure of seeing her perform,
不久，各位將一睹她的舞姿
but right now, let's please raise a glass: To all of us. To Beth. To Nina.
不過現在，讓我們舉杯： 敬在場的各位，敬貝絲，敬尼娜
To beauty.
敬永恆的美
Just a second.
馬上就好！
Come on! I'm about to burst!
快點！我憋不住了！
Hey, it's you!
嗨，是你！
I don't think we ever officially met.
我想我們還沒正式介紹過
- I'm Lily. - Hi, I'm Nina.
- 我叫莉莉 - 嗨，我叫尼娜
Yes, our new Swan Queen.
我知道，新的天鵝女王
- Here, hold this. - Yeah, sure.
- 幫我拿一下 - 好的
You must be so excited.
你一定興奮地要命
Are you freaking out?
你緊張嗎？
- Yeah... - Yeah?
- 是的… - 是嗎？
Oh, it's okay.
沒關係
Oh, I'd be losing my mind.
換成是我，一定會暈頭轉向
I should get back...
我得過去了…
No, no, no, come on, stay.
別…別這樣，等一會
Keep me company.
陪我一會
Excuse me.
失陪
Oh, there you are. Come on.
你在這，跟我來
Hey. They tried to eat you alive, but here you are.
他們恨不得把你吞了，你卻飄然在此
You did well.
表現得很好
- Really? - Mm-hmm.
真的？
Where are you going?
你去哪？
Upper west side.
上西區
Stop at my place for a drink. It's on the way.
順道去我家喝一杯
Thomas, you need to say hello to Karen Holloway.
托馬斯，過去和凱倫·哈羅維打個招呼
A minute more of ass-kissing. I'll be back. Wait for me here, all right?
我得去拍個馬屁，一會就回來 在這等我，好嗎？
Hello, Karen!
你好，凱倫！
Beth!
貝絲！
I'm so sorry to hear you're leaving the company.
真遺憾，你要離開我們
What did you do to get this role?
你是怎麼得到這個角色的？
He always said you were such a frigid little girl.
他總說你缺乏激情
What did you do to make him change his mind?
你怎麼讓他改變了主意？
Did you suck his cock?
和他上床？
Not all of us have to.
不是每個人都需要這麼做
You fucking whore!
你個無恥的婊子！
You're a fucking little whore!
你就是個無恥的小婊子！
Whoa, what's going on here?
冷靜，怎麼回事？
Hey, I need to talk to you.
我得和你談談
- You're drunk. You should go home. - I need to talk to you.
- 你喝醉了，回家吧 - 我得和你談談
No! Don't you do that! Don't you dismiss me like that!
不！你敢！你敢就這樣踢掉我！
My little princess, please. Pull it together.
我的小公主，拜託，冷靜一點
- Come. - I'm coming by later.
- 走吧 - 我會去找你的
I have something for you. It's a token of my appreciation.
我有件東西送給你，以表我的感激之情
- Right. - You make the most of it, Nina.
- 好 - 別客氣，下手狠點，尼娜
Don't worry. It's typical.
別介意，這行就是這樣
Please. I thought it'd be good to talk about the role.
請坐，我們應該談談角色
Drown this a little.
沖談一下拘謹的氣氛
I don't want there to be any boundaries between us.
我們不想彼此有隔閡
- No, me neither. - Good.
- 我也這麼想 - 很好
So... You got a boyfriend?
那麼…你有男朋友嗎？
No.
沒有
Have you had many in the past?
過去交的男朋友多嗎？
A few.
交過幾個
But no one serious.
不過，都不是正式的
You're not a virgin are you?
你不會是處女吧？
No.
不是
So there's nothing to be embarrassed about.
那就用不著害羞
And you enjoy making love?
你喜歡做愛嗎？
Excuse me?
什麼？
Come on, sex.
別大驚小怪，性
Do you enjoy it?
喜歡嗎？
We need to be able to talk about this.
我們必須談這個話題
I've got a little homework assignment for you.
我給你佈置一個家庭作業
Go home and touch yourself.
回家後，自慰
Live a little.
放鬆一下
Well it's late. Lots of work tomorrow.
天晚了，明天還有很多工作
The doorman will find a cab for you.
門房會為你叫出租車
Sounds like quite an evening. I wish I could have been there.
聽起來今晚很精彩，真希望我也能去
You know I asked.
我向他們提過
I know you did. Susie told me.
我知道，蘇茜對我說了
Guess he wanted you all to himself.
我猜他想和你單獨在一起
But why?
可是為什麼？
Don't blame him.
我不怪他
Where'd you get these?
耳環哪來的？
They're fake.
假的
Fooled me.
我以為是真
I can do it.
我自己能行
He must have been by your side all night.
他一定整晚都在你身邊
Showing you off.
帶著你四處招搖
- Oh, Nina... - It's just a rash.
- 尼娜… - 疹子而已
Rash? What are you talking about?
疹子？你在說什麼？
It was worse a few days ago. It's fine already.
前幾天更嚴重，現在好多了
- You've been scratching yourself again. - No I haven't.
- 你一定又用手抓了 - 沒有
Mom!
媽媽！
This disgusting habit...
怎麼有這個壞毛病…
Jesus Christ, I thought you were done with this, Nina.
老天，我以為你改了這個壞毛病，尼娜
Shrugs. You'll keep wearing the shrugs.
披肩，從明天起披肩不許離身
Sit down. You have the white one,
坐下，你有一件白色的
and the pink one. And that'll hide it.
還有一件粉色的，應該能遮住
And then I'll dig out that expensive coverup. We still have some.
然後，我再找一點那種貴粉底 我們還剩一些
No one will see it.
不會有人發現的
Mom, please,
媽媽，別這樣
It's the role, isn't it? It's all this pressure.
因為這個角色，是嗎？壓力太大
I knew it'd be too much. I knew it.
我就知道你承受不了，我就知道
You're all right.
你會沒事的
Beth's in the hospital.
貝絲進醫院了
She had an accident.
發生了車禍
Oh no!
不！
Beth?
貝絲？
What happened?
怎麼回事？
She walked into the street and got hit by a car.
她衝進馬路被車撞了
You know what?
你知道嗎？
I'm almost sure she did it on purpose.
我敢肯定，她是故意的
How do you know?
你怎麼知道？
Because everything Beth does comes from within, from some dark impulse.
因為貝絲做任何事都帶著一股黑暗的衝動
I guess that's what makes her so thrilling to watch.
所以她的表演充滿著快感
So dangerous.
讓人戰慄
Even perfect at times.
某一時刻，甚至完美無缺
But also so damned destructive.
但卻充滿著該死的毀滅性
Was it right after we saw her?
是吵架那天發生的嗎？
Wait, wait, wait. This has nothing to do with you.
等等…這些跟你沒關係
It's not your problem, so don't let yourself be distracted.
和你沒有關係，別擔心
This is your moment, Nina.
現在你是主角，尼娜
Don't let it go.
好好把握
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
Nina?
尼娜？
Sweetie, are you ready for me?
寶貝，我要來嘍？
And... Come on!
加油！
Forget about control, Nina. I want to see passion.
別控制，尼娜，我要看見激情
Stiff like a dead corpse. Let it go.
太僵硬了，沒有生氣，放鬆
Let it go. Let it go.
放鬆，放鬆
And again.
再一次
Feels like you have your diaphragm
感覺你的橫隔膜
is in a bit of a contraction?
有點收縮？
I'm okay.
好
Breathe in to this hand. Breathe in to this hand.
將氣吸入我手的方向，吸氣
Breathe in, all the way. Good.
深吸一口氣，好
And exhale.
呼氣
Does it feel jammed in the front every time you plie?
做挺背曲膝的時候，前面是不是有點僵硬？
Sometimes, not always.
有時會，不常發生
- One more pull, okay? - Okay.
- 再拉一次，好嗎？ - 好
- Is that okay? - Yeah.
- 好點嗎？ - 是的
David, can I ask you a question?
大衛，能問你一個問題嗎？
Honestly, would you fuck that girl?
說實話，你會和那樣的女孩上床嗎？
No.
不會
No one would.
沒人會
Nina...
尼娜
Your dancing is just as frigid...
你的舞蹈缺乏激情
Fuck!
該死！
We're still working here, please. Lights!
我們還在工作，請把燈打開！
The lights!
開燈！
Thank you!
謝謝！
Okay, guys, you can go. Thanks for your patience.
各位，你們可以走了，謝謝
No, no, you stay. You stay.
不是你，你留下
Have fun, you two.
你們好好玩
Okay
好
Come here.
到這來
Come, come, come, come.
過來，過來…
I'll be the Prince.
我來演王子
Let it go. Let it go.
別控制，別控制
Feel my touch.
感覺我的撫摸
Respond to it.
迎合我
Come on.
快
Open your mouth. Open it. Open up.
張開嘴，張開，張開
That was me seducing you,
現在是我在引誘你
when it needs to be the other way around.
應該你引誘我
Please...
等等…
Who is that?
誰在那？
Hey.
嘿
You okay?
你沒事吧？
You can't smoke in here.
你不能在這吸煙
Well, I won't tell if you won't.
你知我知…
So...
所以...
The big day's getting closer and closer, huh?
大日子越來越近，是不是？
Well, I can't wait. I think you're going to be amazing.
我已經等不及了，相信你的表演會很精彩
Thanks.
謝謝
So...
那麼…
Do  you want to talk about it?
你想談談嗎？
It's that hard to.
不知怎麼說
Leroy playing a little too rough for you?
盧萊對你太凶是嗎？
Come on, Nina. He's a prick.
沒事的，尼娜，他是個混蛋
He's brilliant.
他很了不起
Sure, but it's not like he's all warm and fuzzy.
沒錯，可他也很凶
What you don't know is...
你不瞭解他…
Someone's hot for teacher!
有人暗戀老師！
Oh, come on, it's okay. I don't blame you.
別激動，沒事，很正常
I should go home.
我要回家了
Nina, come on. I'm just playing around.
尼娜，別這樣，我開玩笑的
Nina!
尼娜！
Sweetie? What are you doing in there?
寶貝？你在裡面幹什麼？
Again.
再來
Do you have any corrections?
到底什麼問題？
Lily told me that she saw you crying.
莉莉告訴我，看見你在哭
That you were very upset
心情很不好
and that I should take it easy on you.
讓我對你溫和一點
I didn't tell her that.
不是我讓她說的
Maybe you need a little break.
也許你該休息一下
A day or two. Or maybe a month. What do you think?
休息一、兩天，或者一個月，你覺得呢？
She shouldn't have said anything.
她不該亂說話
No, you shouldn't be whining in the first place.
不，是你不該發牢騷
I didn't.
我沒有
You could be brilliant.
你本該更優秀
But you're a coward.
可你是個膽小鬼
Sorry.
對不起
No, stop saying that! That's exactly what I'm talking about.
別再說這句話！這就是你的問題
Stop being so fucking weak.
別再軟弱下去
Again!
再來！
Lily...
莉莉…
Oh, look who's decided to grace us with her presence.
瞧瞧，是誰大架光臨了
I need to talk to you.
我要和你談談
Okay.
好
Now.
馬上
Shut up.
閉嘴
Come on.
來吧
What's up?
什麼事？
You told Thomas about last night?
你和托馬斯說了昨晚的事？
Oh, yeah. I ran into him in the morning and he said you guys were having some trouble.
是啊，早上我碰見他，他說你們遇到了問題
Why would he talk to you?
他為什麼要和你說這些？
Oh, excuse me, your highness.
你說什麼，陛下
I just told him you're working your ass off and I think you'll be great.
我告訴他你很努力，我相信你會很棒的
Well you shouldn't have.
你不該說
Okay.
好
Has he tried anything with you?
他對你毛手毛腳嗎？
He has a reputation.
他可是惡名在外
I have a right to be concerned, Nina. You've been staying late so many nights.
我有理由擔心，尼娜，你每天回來的很晚
Rehearsing. I just hope he isn't taking advantage, that's all.
綵排，我希望他別佔你便宜，就擔心這事
He's not.
他沒有
Good.
很好
I just don't want you to make the same mistake I did.
我不想你走我的老路
Thanks.
謝謝
Not like that.
不是因為你
I just mean as far as my career was concerned.
別像我一樣，毀了事業
What career?
你什麼事業？
The one I gave up to have you.
因為生你放棄的事業
I'm twenty-eight.
我28了
So?
接著說？
Only that...
僅僅…
Only what?
僅僅什麼？
Nothing.
沒什麼
- What? - Nothing.
- 什麼？ - 沒什麼
How is your skin?
你皮膚怎麼樣？
Fine.
很好
- Are you leaving it alone? - Mm-hmm.
還抓沒抓？
Let me see.
讓我看看
- Take off your shirt. - No.
- 脫掉襯衣 - 不
Can I help you?
有事嗎？
Who was that?
是誰？
It was no one.
沒人
Hello?
有誰？
What are you doing here?
怎麼是你？
I just came by to apologize.
我是來道歉的
You're right. I should have never spoken to him about you.
你說的對，我不該和他談你的事
- Sweetheart. - Give me a second.
- 寶貝 - 等一會
- Your dinner... - Mom, please.
- 吃晚飯… - 媽媽，拜託
Oh, she's a trip.
她可真難纏
How do you know where I live?
你怎麼知道我住哪？
I have my ways.
山人自有妙計
Jesus, relax. I got it from Susie in the office.
老天，別緊張，辦公室的蘇茜告訴我的
Look, I feel really shitty about what I did, and I really want to make it up to you.
這件事讓我很不舒服，我真的想彌補一下
So how about I take you out to dinner?
我請你出去吃飯怎麼樣？
- I don't think... - Okay, that's fine.
- 我不知道… - 好吧，沒關係
What about drinks?
喝一杯呢？
Sweetie, you need to rest.
寶貝，你該休息了
- Jesus. - Wait.
- 老天 - 等等
What are you doing?
你幹什麼？
I'm going out.
出去
What? Nina!
什麼？尼娜！
You're on the stage tomorrow.
你明天要上台
I can't believe he calls her that.
他居然那麼叫她
- It's so gross. - I think it's sweet.
- 真噁心 - 我倒覺得很貼心
Little Princess?
小公主？
- He probably calls every girl that. - No way.
- 他可能對每個女孩都這麼叫 - 不可能
That's just for Beth.
只對貝絲
Well, I bet he'll be calling you Little Princess any day now.
我打賭，過幾天他就會叫你小公主
I don't know about that.
我不知道
Oh, sure he will. Just got to let him lick your pussy.
他會的，上床的時候可別饒了他
Cheeseburger, extra bloody.
乾酪漢堡包，大份番茄醬
Let me know if that's juicy enough for you.
醬不夠可以叫我
Oh, I will.
我會的
You have enough cheese?
乾酪夠嗎？
No, but you do.
你可多的很（意思是你很煩）
Enjoy.
慢用
All right.
來
Wanna spruce up?
想打扮打扮嗎？
What, I carry a spare
幹嘛，我帶著備用
in case I wake up somewhere unexpected.
以防玩過頭
So how is he?
他怎麼樣？
Thomas.
托馬斯
I wouldn't know.
我不知道
- Oh, come on. - I really don't want to talk about that.
- 少來 - 我真的不想談他
Okay.
好吧
You really need to relax.
你真得放鬆放鬆
One for you,
一顆給你
one for me.
一顆給我
Oh, and don't worry. It's pure, I promise. I brought it with me straight from San Francisco.
別擔心，貨很純，我保證 是從舊金山帶過來的
What is it?
這是什麼？
Are you kidding?
開玩笑？
You've never rolled?
你從沒嗑過藥？
Oh, relax. Here. It'll loosen you up.
別擔心，它能幫你放鬆下來
Wait till you see the night sky.
你會看見無垠的夜空
How long does it last?
藥力會持續多久？
A couple hours, tops.
最多，幾個小時
It's okay.
不用了
Okay.
好吧
Nina, hi!
尼娜！
I thought we could use some company. So this is Tom and this is Jerry.
我們有伴了，這是湯姆，這是傑瑞
- Actually it's Andrew. - Tom.
- 實際上，我叫安德魯 - 湯姆
- I have to go... - Oh, no you can't go. I just got us some drinks.
- 我得走了… - 不行，不能走，我剛點了酒
I shouldn't...
我不應該…
We're on the stage tomorrow.
我們明天要上台
So what are you going to do? Go home to Mommy?
去哪？回家找媽媽？
Come on, live a little.
來吧，玩一會
It's just a couple hours, right?
藥力只有幾個小時，是嗎？
Tops.
是的
Cheers.
乾杯
You haven't told me who you are.
你還沒告訴我你是誰
I'm a dancer.
我是個舞蹈演員
No, I mean your name.
不是這意思，你的名字
- Oh. Nina. - So are you two sisters?
- 尼娜 - 你倆是姐妹？
- Yes. - No.
- 是的 - 不是
- Blood sisters. - We dance in the same company.
- 閨中姐妹 - 我們在同一個團跳舞
Ah, ballerinas. No wonder you two look alike.
芭蕾舞女演員，難怪你們長的這麼像
I see now. Tom and Jerry here are gay lovers.
我也看出來了，你倆是同志小情人
- Very funny. - I like to amuse myself.
- 真幽默 - 我喜歡自娛自樂
I've never been to the ballet.
我從來沒接觸過芭蕾
Then you are definitely not gay.
這麼看，你絕對不是同志
I mean, it's kind of boring, isn't it?
我是說，芭蕾有點枯燥，是不是？
- Be honest. - No it's not.
- 老實說 - 不，不是這樣
You know what? It's just not for everyone.
這麼說吧，不是每個人都能接受
You should come sometime. I can comp you tickets whenever you want.
找個時間過來看看，我給你們贈券
Yeah. Yeah.
好，好
- Yeah, that would be neat. Thanks. - Okay well...
- 那真是太棒了，謝謝 - 好了…
I think it's time for another round.
我們再喝一杯
Bottoms up.
乾杯
So what are you guys working on now?
你們在排什麼戲？
Sorry.
不好意思
Swan Lake.
天鵝湖
Yeah?
是嗎？
You know it?
你看過？
No, not really.
沒有
Heard of it.
聽說過
What's it about?
說的什麼？
It's about a girl who gets turned into a swan,
是說一個女孩被人變成了天鵝
and she needs love to break the spell.
她需要愛的力量打破詛咒
But her prince falls for the wrong girl,
可她的王子卻愛上了不該愛的人
and so she kills herself.
於是她自殺了
It's not a happy ending then.
是個悲劇
It's beautiful, actually.
實際上，很美
Like you.
像你一樣
Huh?
什麼？
I said you're beautiful.
我說你很美
That's funny?
很好笑？
Looks like someone might be rolling.
某人的情緒上來嘍
All right, come on. Come on, it's time to go dance.
好了，過來，去跳舞
Nina!
尼娜！
Hey, what the fuck? Where you going?
搞什麼？你去哪？
Where are you going?
你去哪？
Do you have any idea what time it is?
你知道現在幾點了嗎？
Late?
很晚了？
Where have you been?
你去了哪？
To the moon and back.
到月亮上去了
- You've been drinking. - Ding ding ding ding ding!
- 你喝酒了 - 猜 對 啦！
- What else? - Hmm?
還有什麼？
What else have you been doing?
你還做了什麼？
Oh, you want to know their names?
原來你想知道他們的名字？
- You need to sleep this off. - There were two. Tom and Jerry.
- 快去睡覺 - 是兩個人，湯姆和傑瑞
- Be quiet, Nina. - And I fucked them both.
- 閉嘴，尼娜 - 我和他們都上了床
Shut your mouth!
閉嘴！
- Don't come in here. - What's this?
- 不許進來 - 你幹什麼？
It's called privacy. I'm not twelve anymore.
懂不懂什麼叫隱私，我不再是小女孩了
- You're not my Nina right now... - Leave me alone!
- 你現在腦子不清楚 - 走開！
Sweat girl.
小甜心
Why didn't you wake me up?
為什麼不叫醒我？
I'm moving out.
我要搬出去
My music!
是我的曲子！
Thomas, I am so sorry.
托馬斯，真對不起
Keep on going.
繼續跳
Go get warmed up.
去熱身
That was good.
很好
Actually, really good.
非常之好
Okay, let's take ten.
好，休息十分鐘
Look, he just wanted to mark it and asked me to step up, okay?
他只是讓我示範一下，明白嗎？
I overslept.
我睡過了頭
Oops. But hey, at least you had a good time, right?
慘嘍，不過你玩很開心，對嗎？
You put something in my drink.
你在我酒裡下了東西
Yeah.
沒錯
And then you just took off in the morning.
早上卻一個人先走了
In the morning?
早上？
Yeah, you slept over.
你在我家過的夜
Um, no.
沒有
Unless your name's Tom and you had a dick.
除非你叫湯姆，還長了一根老二
What, Nina?
我們怎麼了，尼娜？
Did you have some sort of lesbian wet dream about me?
是不是在夢裡和我上床了？
- Stop. - Oh my God!
- 別說了 - 老天！
Oh my God, you did! You fantasized about me!
老天，是真的！我成了你的性幻想對象！
- Shut up! - Was I good?
- 閉嘴！ - 我床上功夫好嗎？
The final act.
最後一幕
You're trying to dance.
你的最後一場戲
You've tasted your dream! Touched it!
夢想幾乎成真！如此真實！
Only to have it crushed!
可卻被砸得粉碎！
Your heart is broken,
你的心破碎了！
wounded. Your life force fading.
受傷了，你的生命在枯萎
The blood drips.
鮮血滴滴下墜
The Black Swan stole your love. There is only one way to end the pain.
黑天鵝偷走了你的愛人 只有一條路可以熄滅痛苦
You are not fearful, but filled with acceptance.
你不再恐懼，接受了命運的安排
And you look down at Rothbart,
你垂目看了看羅斯巴
and then at the Prince,
又看了看王子
and then, yes, at the audience.
之後，對，注視觀眾
And then you jump.
然後，縱身躍下
Go ahead. Jump. Jump!
快點，跳，沒事的，跳！
Okay, everybody get a drink of water, then it's notes.
好了，大家去喝杯水，然後做分段練習
You lost weight.
你瘦了
Take off your shrug, please.
請脫下披肩
Very good.
很好
Face front. We're almost done.
向前看，快好了
And that's it. Okay.
完成，好了
We're done. Thank you very much.
好了，非常感謝
Georgina, I'm Lily. Thomas sent me...
喬治娜，我叫莉莉，托馬斯讓我來…
Yes, we have to get you measured for the Swan Queen costumes.
我知道，給你也做一身天鵝女王的服裝
What's she doing here?
她怎麼在這？
He made me your alternate.
他讓我做你的替補
Look, it's just in case.
只是以防萬一
Thomas. Thomas.
托馬斯，托馬斯
- Thomas. - Yes?
- 托馬斯 - 什麼事？
It can't be her.
不可以用她
Okay, why don't you just go. I'll catch up later.
你先去，我一會來
What's going on?
怎麼了？
Lily... You made her my alternate?
莉莉...你讓她做我的替補？
There's always an alternate. Lily is the best choice.
這是慣例，莉莉是最佳人選
No, she wants my role.
不，她想頂掉我
Every dancer in the world wants your role.
每個人都想頂掉你
No, this is different. She is after me.
不，這不一樣，她別有用心
- She is trying to replace me. - Nobody is after you.
- 她想取代我 - 沒有人別有用心
- No, please believe me...
不，請相信我…
I know it's been a struggle. But you just had a breakthrough this morning.
我知道你壓力很大 不過，你早上的表演很有突破
Tomorrow is yours. Just give a great performance and you won't have to worry about Lily or anybody else.
明天是屬於你的，演一齣好戲，誰也不用想
Now go home and rest.
現在回家，好好休息
From the vision again.
從「幻夢」再來一次
What happened?
怎麼回事？
I've got a life.don't work too hard. It's a big day tomorrow.
我有我的生活，別太拼了，明天是大日子
I'm still working in here.
我還在工作
Could you please turn the lights back on?
請把燈打開好嗎？
Hello?
有人嗎？
What are you doing here?
你來幹什麼？
I'm so sorry.
對不起
I know how it feels now. She's trying to replace me.
現在我才瞭解那種感受，她想取代我
What do I do?
我該怎麼辦？
You stole my things?
你偷我東西？
I was just trying to be perfect, like you.
我想完美，像你一樣
Perfect?
完美？
I'm not perfect.
我一點也不完美
I'm nothing.
我什麼都不是
Nothing!
什麼都不是！
Nothing, nothing!
不是！不是！
Sweet girl.
乖女兒
Mommy?
媽媽？
Sweet girl. Sweet girl.
乖女兒，乖女兒
Stop!
閉嘴！
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
Sweetie?
寶貝？
Nina?
尼娜？
Nina!
尼娜！
Go away!
走開！
Open the door!
開門！
Open the door, Nina!
開門！尼娜！
Nina!
尼娜！
Get out!
出去！
- What's wrong with you? - Get out!
- 你到底怎麼了？ - 出去！
- Get out! - What do you see?
- 出去！ - 你看見什麼了？
Get out!
出去！
It's okay.
沒事了
I'm here.
媽在這
You were scratching all night.
你整晚都在抓
Where's my clock?
我的鬧鐘呢？
- Don't worry about that. - What time is it?
- 別管了 - 幾點了？
- The show is tonight, I have to... - No, no, no, no.
- 今晚演出，我必須… - 不行，不行…
Don't worry.
別擔心
I called the theater and I told them you aren't feeling well.
我給劇院打了電話，告訴他們你不舒服
I have to go!
我一定得去！
- No. No, you don't. - Let go of me.
- 不行，不行，不能去 - 放開我
You're staying in here until you feel better.
你身子不好，不能離開
Where is it?
門把手呢？
This role is destroying you.
這個角色會毀了你
- Move. Move! - Nina...!
- 過去！過去！ - 尼娜…！
- What happened to my sweet girl? - She's gone!
- 我的乖女兒到底怎麼了？ - 她死了！
Nina! Oh, Nina!
尼娜！尼娜！
No, please!
不，求你！
- You're not well! - Let go of me!
- 你生病了！ - 放開我！
You can't handle this.
你承受不了
I can't?
我承受不了？
I'm the Swan Queen. You're the one who never left the corps.
我是天鵝女王，而你只能一輩子跑龍套
Nina!
尼娜！
What are you doing here?
你來幹什麼？
Nina?
尼娜？
She was supposed to be sick.
她不是病了嗎？
Give us a minute.
等等，我和她談一會
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？
I'm fine.
我很好
Nina.
尼娜
What?
幹什麼？
I've already asked Lily.
我已經讓莉莉上了
Have you announced it?
你正式宣佈了嗎？
After Beth, do you really need another controversy?
經過貝絲那件事，你還想製造新話題嗎？
I'm here, Thomas.
我來了，托馬斯
I'm doing it.
我來演
The only person standing in your way is you.
你的本性在障礙你
It's time to let it go. Lose yourself.
趕走它，釋放你自己
White Swan, up in ten.
白天鵝，十分鐘後上場
What are you doing? You need to be upstage.
你在幹什麼？該你上台了
You suck.
你演得真差
Okay, Nina.
尼娜
What the fuck?
搞什麼？
- Are you okay? - Nina, are you okay?
- 你沒事吧？ - 尼娜，你沒事吧？
Can you tell me what the fuck happened?
你說，到底他媽怎麼回事？
- It wasn't my fault. He dropped me. - This is a fucking disaster.
- 不是我的錯，是他失的手 - 真他媽失敗
Rough start, huh? Must have been pretty humiliating.
開局不順吧？一定丟死人了
Get out of my room.
滾出我的房間
I'm worried about the next act.
我真為下一場捏一把汗
I'm just not sure you're feeling up to it.
我覺得你心有餘而力不足
Stop. Please stop.
別說了，快別說了
How about I dance the Black Swan for you?
黑天鵝還是讓我跳吧？
Leave me alone!
走開！
My turn!
該我了！
Black Swan, places in five.
黑天鵝，五分鐘後上場
Come on.
快過來
Good job. Fifteen to the last act.
跳得漂亮，十五分鐘以後，最後一幕
Hey. You were amazing.
嘿，你真絕了
Seriously, I know that things got a little messed up between us,
說真的，我知道我們之間有點小誤會
but I mean, holy shit, you completely blew me away!
但是，老天，我服你了！
Okay, well I guess that's it.
好了，不說了
So I'll let you finish. Bye.
不妨礙你了，再見
Can you hear them?
聽見觀眾的歡呼嗎？
They love you!
他們愛你！他們愛你！
My little princess, I always knew you had it in you.
我的小公主，我就知道你有那股魔力
Come on. Let's take you out.
來，我們一起出去
Go get some help.
快去叫人！
What did you do?
你都幹了什麼？
- I felt it. - What?
- 我感覺到了 - 什麼？
I felt perfect.
完美
I was perfect.
我完美了
Nina! Nina! Nina!
尼娜！尼娜！尼娜！